Guide to the Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union, Local 3 Records and Photographs WAG.135
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union, Local 3 Records and Photographs
1902-1996
1955-1986
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union. Local 3 (Long Island City, N.Y.)
Spratley, Carol Hofheinz
WAG.135
33.5 Linear Feet in 34 record cartons and 1 folder in shared housing
This collection contains the minutes, officers' papers, subject files and photographs files of the Bakery Confectionery and Tobacco Workers International Union, Local 3, including executive and grievance boards, general membership meetings as well as the papers of Presidents Frank Dutto, and Harry Lorber and Business Agent Michael Sandroff. Topics range from bargaining and arbitration to elections and anniversary dinners. There is information on specific bake shops from the small family-run shops to large corporate bakeries.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Bakers Union Local 3 was established in 1955 with the merger of locals 1, 3, 17, 164, 288, and 579. During the Bakery and Confectionery Workers International Union Convention of 1951, a resolution was passed to implement the merger of all New York bakery locals. Frequent jurisdictional disputes between rival locals were undermining the collective strength of bakers within the industry. Over a dozen local unions representing the interests of workers in the baking industry in New York took part in merger discussions sponsored by the International, but by 1955 only six of the participating unions consented to merge.
Beginning in the 1850s, New York played an important role in the evolution of the unionization of the trade. Owning to the large immigrant presence in New York, unions were originally established according to nationality. The German Bakers, the Jewish Bread Bakers, the French-Italian Bakers, the Spanish Bakers, among others, each existed as separate, independently organized entities. The result of these nationality-organized unions led to a frequent overlapping of jurisdictions within the Greater New York area. As early as 1937, a conference of the Bakery Workers International Union made an effort to address ongoing jurisdiction disputes by encouraging these disparate organizations to unify. Over the course of the next decade a series of mergers took place but nothing compared with the magnitude of the creation of Local 3 in 1955. With its establishment, Local 3 became a dominate force in the baking industry in New York and an important presence on the national front.
Under the dynamic leadership of its first president Frank Dutto, Local 3 would grapple with many challenges. Dutto had risen from the rank and file to become President first of Local 87, then Local 1, and subsequently Local 3. In 1958, Dutto appeared before the McClellan Committee in connection with the sponsorship of a fund-raising dinner for Bakery's vice-president, Max Kralstein. During these hearings Dutto invoked the 5th Amendment when questioned about his affiliation with the Communist Party. Throughout his remaining tenure as president, the taint of these hearings left him vulnerable. Perhaps the greatest upheaval during these years stemmed from corruption charges in the International. In 1958 the Bakery and Confectionery Workers International Union (BCW) was ousted by the AFL-CIO after International President James Cross was indicted for embezzlement. When the AFL chartered the American Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International (ABC), the baking industry fractured on an International level and locally there arose bitter jurisdictional disputes. The mending of this destabilizing division within the International became of primary concern to Local 3 under Dutto's stewardship. Local 3 would remain affiliated with the BCW but at the forefront of efforts to heal the split in the International. In 1959, Local 3 served a vital role in the formation of the Local Unions Reunification Committee. Reunification occurred in 1969 after a twelve-year struggle.
One of the chief concerns of the Local 3 executive board during its early years was the evolution of a standard contract and the development of uniform welfare and pension plans. With the merger of the six unions, Local 3 was now responsible for the negotiation of agreements with over 750 bakery employers each with differing provisions for wages, benefits and shop conditions. The turning point in the establishment of a standard contract came with the general strike of 1959 in which New York locals affiliated with both the BCW and the ABC struck in concert and remained off the job for over 3 months. With the settlement came the first uniform agreement in the baking industry in New York. Within months of the settlement, the union's new headquarters in Long Island City were completed and dedicated in June of 1959. In celebration of the event, Local 3 held its first Cake Show. Cake Shows would become annual events showcasing the talents of the skilled pastry, cake, and bread bakers. These occasions, along with the monthly publication of "Local 3 News," served to organize and bolster the membership of the growing union.
With the death of Frank Dutto in 1969, the former Secretary-Treasurer Harry Rubenstein took over the presidency and served from 1970 to 1973. These years brought a series of new mergers with Local 3 by other unions that sought greater bargaining strength and unity. By the end of Rubenstein's tenure, Matzoh-Noodle Local 269, Jersey Local 167, Bagel Local 338, and Perth Amboy Local 190 had all merged with Local 3. In 1973 the most significant merger since 1955 occurred when the powerful Cake Bakers Union Local 51 merged with Local 3. Jurisdictional disputes that had plagued these rival unions were brought to an end with this merger. Under the terms of the agreement Rubenstein retired and Harry Lorber, former Secretary-Treasurer of Local 51, assumed the position of President of Local 3.
Lorber served as president for the next 16 years, until 1989. Trained as a lawyer, Lorber was a member of the International General Executive Board, chairman of the New York Union Label and Service Trades organization, and chairman of the Baking Industry Labor-Management Apprenticeship Council. In addition he was the chairman of both the Cake Bakers Union Welfare Fund, and of the Local 3 Welfare and Pension Fund. During this era the Union and the baking industry would undergo great changes. Issues related to automation and corporate manufacturing dominated the 1970s and 1980s, as evidenced by the protracted contract negotiations with corporate giants such as Drakes and Entenmann's.
In 1989 Lorber retired and was succeeded by Secretary-Treasurer Ernst Schenkman in December of that year. Following the sudden death of Schenkman in a car accident one month later in January of 1990, the then Secretary-Treasurer Narciso Martas became the fourth President of Local 3.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains the minutes, correspondence and chronological files of Locals 1, 3, 17, 164, 388, and 579, including executive and grievance boards, general membership meetings as well as the papers of Presidents Frank Dutto, and Harry Lorber and Business Agent Michael Sandroff. Also included in the collection are documents on standard contract negotiations as well as collective bargaining negotiations between individual shops and corporate entities. General files include records pertaining to by-laws, elections, legal disputes and grievances, the Cross indictment, and union label samples, amongst others. Souvenir programs and photographs from a variety of locals are also included.
Arrangement
Material in Series I is grouped by organizations and arranged chronologically within each grouping. Material in Series II is arranged alphabetically and chronologically. Series III is arranged chronologically, and Series IV though VIII are arranged alphabetically. Series IX has not been arranged by an archivist.
The records are organized into the following series:
Series I: Minutes, 1920-1984
Series II: Officers' Papers, 1946-1987
Series III: Bargaining and Arbitration, 1954-1987
Series IV: Shop Files, 1964-1989
Series V: Local 3, Subjects, 1954-1989
Series VI: Welfare and Pension Fund, 1955-1988
Series VII: General Files, 1902-1978
Series VIII: Souvenir Programs, 1930-1993
Series IX: Photographs, 1950-1990s
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New Yorkers at Work Oral History Collection (OH 001) contains interviews with members and officers of Bakers Local 3
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union, AFL-CIO - Local 3 in 1996. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1996.017 and 1996.018.
A gift of a dues ledger from Local 6 was donated by Carol Hofheinz in August 2012. The accession number associated with this gift is 2013.026.
In 2023, one folder of materials documenting the incorporation of the Journeymen Bakers Union, Local 1, were found by a researcher using Box 1 of the American Association of University Professors Committee on Academic Freedom Records (TAM 407); the exterior markings of the folder, as well as their contents, indicated that they are from WAG 135. They were accessioned into WAG 135 as accession 2025.045. There is no other information about these materials' provenance.
Collective labor agreements |x Bakery employees.; New York (N.Y.).; Bakery employees |x Labor unions.; Labor unions -- United States.; Bylaws (administrative records); Minutes (administrative records); Union labels.; Correspondence.; Legal documents.; Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union. Union Label and Service Trades Department; Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union. General Executive Board; Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union. Labor-Management Apprentice Council; Sandroff, Mac; American Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union; Schenkman, Ernst; Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union. Local 3 (Long Island City, N.Y.); Martas, Narciso; Rubenstein, Harry R., 1951-; Dutto, Frank, d. 1969; Lorber, Harry; Cross, James; Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union. Local 3 (Long Island City, N.Y.); Spratley, Carol Hofheinz
- Series I: Minutes, 1920-1984
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains the minutes of five of the original six unions (Locals 1, 3, 17, 164, 579) that merged to create Local 3 in 1955 as well as a number of other local unions that subsequently merged with Local 3. The locals are arranged in numerically ascending order. Some of the minutes from the earlier years are in English, Yiddish and German (consult Box & Folder List) and reflect the multi-ethnic make-up of the trade. Within this series can also be found the minutes and transcripts related to pre-merger meetings, and included are the minutes of the Baking Industry Labor-Management Apprenticeship Council of Greater New York on which Harry Lorber served. (Note: The 1950-1951 minutes of Local 17 were received in disarray. The precise original order is unclear, but approximate order by month has been restored).
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers (German), Aug 1920 - Jun 1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Materials in German.
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers-Arrangements Committee, Aug 1922 - Feb 1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers-Board of Directors, Feb 1923 - Mar 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers-Board of Directors, Feb 1926 - Aug 1936 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Materials in German and English.
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers-Board of Directors, Aug 1935 - Jan 1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Materials in English.
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers-Board of Directors, Jan 1948 - Jan 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers-Board of Director, Dec 1953 - Dec 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers-Contract Negotiation Committee, Nov 1953 - Dec 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers-Editorial Board, Mar 1954 - Dec 1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers-Labor Committee, May 1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers-Membership, Jan 1948 - Jan 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers-Membership, Dec 1953 - Dec 1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers-Merger Committee, Apr 1954 - Jan 1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers-Organizing Committee, Mar 1954 - Sep 1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers-Retail Shop Minutes, Feb 1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers-Shop Council, May 1954 - Nov 1954 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Local 1, Amalgamated Food Workers-Wholesale Bread and Cake Shop, Feb 1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Old Local 3, Executive Board, Jan 1947 - Oct 1949 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Old Local 3, Executive Board, Mar 1952 - Sep 1954 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Old Local 3, Executive Board, Sep 1954 - Jun 1955 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Old Local 3, Membership, Mar 1948 - May 1955 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Local 3, Executive Board, Jun 1955 - Mar 1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Local 3, Executive Board, Mar 1957 - Jul 1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Local 3, Executive Board (Handwritten Notes), Oct 1973 - Dec 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Local 3, Administrative Board, Nov 1960 - May 1961 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Local 3, Administrative Board, May 1961 - Dec 1961 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Local 3, Administrative Board, Dec 1961 - Oct 1962 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Local 3, Administrative Board, Aug 1963 - Feb 1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Local 3, Administrative Board (Handwritten Notes), undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Local 3, Administrative Staff Meeting (Handwritten Notes), Mar 4, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Local 3, Business Agents Meeting (Handwritten Notes), Jun 1, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Local 3, Coordinating Committee (Handwritten Notes), 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Local 3, Departmental Coordinating Committee, Sep 1966 - Aug 1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Local 3, Executive Board Attendance Record, Jan 1969 - Feb 1973 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Local 3, Grievance Board, Aug 1955 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Local 3, Grievance Board, Jan 1957 - Dec 1958 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Local 3, Membership, Jun 1956 - Feb 1957 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Local 3, Membership, Mar 1957 - May 1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Local 3, Membership (Handwritten), 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Local 3, Policy Committee (Handwritten), Apr 7, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Local 3, Shop Council Meetings (General, Wholesale, Retail), Oct 1959 - Oct 1962 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Local 3, Staff Meetings (Handwritten), 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Local 3, Staff Meeting, Apr 1977 - Dec 1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Local 3, Staff Meeting, Jan 1978 - Dec 1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Local 3, Staff Meeting, Jan 1979 - Dec 1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Local 3, Staff Meeting, Jan 1980 - Dec 1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Local 3, Staff Meeting, Jan 1981 - Dec 1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Local 3, Staff Meeting, Jan 1982 - Dec 1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Local 3, Staff Meeting, Jan 1983 - Dec 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Local 3, Staff Meeting, Jan 1984 - Dec 1984 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Local 3, Staff Meeting, Feb 1985 - May 1985 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Local 3, Structure and Finance Committees, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Local 3, Trial Committee, Oct 17, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Local 3, Welfare and Pension Funds-Trustee Meetings, Mar 1956 - Aug 1956 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Local 3, Wholesale Bread Contract Meeting (Handwritten and Typed), Oct 27, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Local 17, Executive Board and Membership, Dec 1931 - Aug 1938 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Local 17, Executive Board and Membership, Sep 1938 - Oct 1941 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Local 17, Executive Board and Membership, Mar 1947 - May 1949 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Local 17, Executive Board and Membership, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Local 17, Executive Board and Membership, Jan 1952 - Dec 1954 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Local 17, Executive Board and Membership, Jan 1955 - May 1955 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Local 51, Executive Board and Membership, Nov 1942 - Jan 1946 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Local 51, Executive Board and Membership, Jan 1946 - Nov 1947 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Local 51, Executive Board and Membership, Nov 1947 - Nov 1949 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Local 51, Executive Board and Membership, Nov 1949 - Jun 1951 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Local 51, Executive Board and Membership, Jun 1951 - May 1953 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Local 51, Special Meeting (Transcript), Aug 24, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Local 51, Special Meeting (Transcript), Oct 1954 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Local 51, Executive Board and Membership, Jun 1953 - Jan 1955 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Local 51, Executive Board and Membership, Dec 1957 - Feb 1961 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Local 51, Cake Bakers Union Welfare Fund-Trustees' Meetings, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Local 87, Executive Board, Jan 1938 - Dec 1938 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - [Local 102], 1931-1934 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Materials in Italian.
  - Local 164, Executive Board and Membership, Dec 1928 - Oct 1948 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Local 164, Membership, Nov 1948 - Apr 1955 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Local 164, Executive Board, Oct 1941 - Jan 1945 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Local 164, Executive Board, Jan 1952 - Jan 1955 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Local 164, Executive Board, Jan 1952 - Jun 1955 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Local 164, Financial Committee, Feb 1942 - Mar 1951 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Local 164, Westchester Branch, Executive Board and Membership, Jan 1947 - Mar 1950 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Local 338, Bagel Bakers Union-Executive Board, Sep 1944 - Jan 1955 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Materials in English and Yiddish.
  - Local 338, Executive and Membership, Jan 1955 - Feb 1959 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Local 338, Executive Board, Jan 1962- Dec 1962 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Local 338, Executive Board, Jan 1963 - Feb 1964 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Local 338, Executive Board, Mar 1964 - Dec 1964 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Local 338, Executive Board, Jan 1965 - Feb 1966 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Local 338, Executive Board, Mar 1966 - Dec 1966 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Local 338, Executive Board, Jan 1967 - Jun 1968 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Local 338, Membership, Jan 1962 - Jun 1968 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Local 338, Special Nomination Meetings, Apr 1963 - Dec 1967 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Local 507, Executive Board, Sep 1938 - Jan 1947 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Local 507, Executive Board, Jul 1939 - Oct 1941 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Materials in Yiddish.
  - Local 579, Executive Board, Oct 1946 - Dec 1947 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Local 579, Executive Board, Jan 1948 - Dec 1949 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Local 579, Minutes, Mar 1945 - Nov 1948 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Local 579, Membership, Sep 1946 - May 1955 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Local 579, Minutes, Mar 1945 - Nov 1948 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Local 579, Minutes, Nov 1948 - Jul 1950 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Local 579, Minutes, Aug 1950 - Sep 1952 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Baking Industry Labor-Management Apprenticeship Council of Greater New York, 1966-1969 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Baking Industry Labor-Management Apprenticeship Council of Greater New York, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Baking Industry Labor-Management Apprenticeship Council of Greater New York, Jan 1977 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Merger, Locals 79, 505, 509 (Local 579), 1941-1942 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Merger, Locals 1, 3, 17, 164, 288, 579, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Merger-Locals 1, 3, 17, 164, 288, 579, Dec 1954 - Apr 1956 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Merger Committee (Locals 3, 338), 1971 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Merger Committee (Locals 3, 190), 1971 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Merger Committee (Locals 3, 51), 1972 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Series II: Officers' Papers, 1946-1987
  This series contains the papers of Presidents Frank Dutto and Harry Lorber and includes two slim folders of the papers of Michael (Mac) Sandroff who served as Business Agent and Editor of the "Local 3 News" from 1955 until his retirement. Unfortunately the absence of many of Dutto's papers in the Collection belies his extensive activities. Of particular interest is an election leaflet from 1947 bearing his picture, and a map with the location of his cemetery plot. The bulk of the material in this series belongs to Lorber. In addition to general files and correspondence related to his activities with Locals 3 and 51, Lorber's papers document his presence at a score of hearings as a member of the International General Executive Board, as well as his involvement with the Baking Industry Labor-Management Apprenticeship Council. He was often called upon as a public speaker and a folder of his speeches can be found in this series.
  - Dutto Papers, Articles and Biographical Information, 1946-1969 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Dutto Papers, Election Leaflet, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Dutto Papers, General Files (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Dutto Papers, "City of Hope" Program, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Dutto Papers, Specialty Local Wholesalers, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Dutto Papers, Map of Dutto Grave Site, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Lorber Papers, Articles and Biographical Information, 1960-1979 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Lorber Papers, General Files and Correspondence, 1947-1952 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Lorber Papers, General Files and Correspondence, 1959-1970 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Lorber Papers, General Files and Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Lorber Papers, General Files and Correspondence, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Lorber Papers, General Files and Correspondence, Jan 1976 - Jun 1976 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Lorber Papers, General Files and Correspondence, Jul 1976 - Dec 1976 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Lorber Papers, General Files and Correspondence, 1977-1980 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Lorber Papers, Eastern Central State Bargain Conference, 1975-1984 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Lorber Papers, Employment Agreement with Cake Bakers Union Welfare Fund, 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Lorber Papers, Industrial Relations Research Association-Labor Relations & Arbitration, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Lorber Papers, International Foundation of Employment Benefit Plans '79 Annual Conference-Lorber Moderator, Oct 1979 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Lorber Papers, International Association of Industrial Accident Board and Commissions, Sep 1979 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Lorber Papers, Members Problems, 1973-1975 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Lorber Papers, Notes from Meetings, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Lorber Papers, Notes from Meetings, 1977-1982 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Lorber Papers, Occupational Safety & Health Labor-Management Training Program, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Lorber Papers, Personal Stationery, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Lorber Papers, Political & Legislative Letters, 1949-1952 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Lorber Papers, Political & Legislative Letters, 1968, 1977-1981 1986 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Lorber Papers, Speeches, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Lorber Papers, Speeches, 1979, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Lorber Papers, Wheat Bill & Junk Food Bill, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Sandroff Papers, unsorted, 1950-1959, 1960-1969 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Sandroff Papers, Class (School of Industrial Labor Relations at Cornell)-Handouts and Notes, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Lorber Papers, Hearings-Benjamin v. Local 354 (Elmira, NY), Dec 1971 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Lorber Papers, Hearings-Benjamin v. Local 252 (Calgary, Alberta), Dec 1971 - Jan 1972 (Box 11, Folder 2)